A Guide to the World War II Photographs, 1935 (1941-1944) 1945
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
World War II Photographs, 1935 (1941-1944) 1945
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
8654
This collection consists of ca. 8000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Scope and Content Information
The photographs chiefly record activities on the home front. Topics include agriculture; civilian defense; conservation and rationing; conversion of domestic products to war materiel; defense housing; the economy; Lend-Lease; and manpower including shots of baseball players as shipyard workers. Virginia scenes include the Shenandoah Valley, Forts Story, Belvoir, Monroe and Meyer; Langley Air Field; day care in Alexandria and youth in Roanoke.
Also various commissions, boards and offices that include photographs of Eleanor Roosevelt and Carl Sandburg; a 1943 series called "Portraits of America"; aviation production; maritime shipbuilding including scenes at Newport News and Norfolk, Va.; production of metals, power, army vehicles, and weaponry; propaganda; relocation of Japanese Americans; salvage; the Tennessee Valley Authority; and civilian victory campaigns.
Military subjects include Allied leaders at the Casablanca conference and elsewhere, particularly Roosevelt, Churchill, Stalin, Harriman, Stettinius, Stimson, Wallace, Eisenhower, Halsey. Marshall, Patton, Rickenbacker, Giraud, deGaulle, Eleanor Roosevelt, Madame Chiang Kai-Shek and Getulio Vargas; as well as the African, European, Atlantic, Far Eastern, and Pacific theatres; and entertainment including well-known U.S.O. performers.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically.
Contents List
- Agriculture 1942-1943 (Box 1)
  Includes "Food in Britain", "Land Erosion and Terracing"
- Agriculture: Guayule Cultivation for Rubber 1942 Nov (Box 1)
- Agriculture: Mexican Cotton Pickers 1942 Nov (Box 1)
- Agriculture: Women Workers 1942 Sep (Box 1)
- Agriculture: Workers and Training 1942-1944 (Box 1)
  Includes "Farm Training Program" and "School Boys Training for Agriculture"
- Allied Leaders 1942-1943 (Box 1)
  Includes "Allied Military Conference in India," "America's Leaders--radio program, 9 Aug 1942," "General Dwight D. Eisenhower," "French Military Leaders," "Admiral William F. Halsey," "Robert P. Patterson, Under Secretary of War," "Captain Eddie Rickenbacker and Secretary of War Henry L. Stimson," "Eleanor Roosevelt and Madame Chiang Kai Shek," "Meeting of Stalin, Churchill, and Harriman," "Edward R. Stettinius, Lend-Lease Administrator," and "Henry Wallace, Vice-President"
- Allied Leaders: President Franklin D. Roosevelt and others during the Casablanca Conferences 1943 Jan, 2 folders (Box 1)
  Includes "Winston Churchill," "General Henri Honore Giraud, French High Commissioner and President Charles DeGaulle of France," "Major General George S. Patton, Jr. and General George C. Marshall," "President Getulio Vargas of Brazil," "in French Morocco," and "in Liberia and Africa"
- Allies 1942-1944 (Box 1)
  Includes "Canadian Workers," "Chinese Seamen on United Nations' Vessels," "Combined Munitions Assignments Board," "Icelandic Parliament," and "Italian Government after War"
- Civilian Defense 1942-1943 (Box 1)
  Includes "Fire Prevention", "Uniforms," and "War Emergency Radio Service"
- Civilian Defense: Air Raid Protection 1941 Dec (Box 1)
- Civilian Defense 1942 Mar (Box 1)
- Civilian Protection 1941 Oct (Box 1)
- Conservation: Durable Goods 1942 Feb (Box 2)
- Conservation: Food Rationing 1942-1943 (Box 2)
  Includes "Meat Rationing", "Share the Meat Recipes", "Sugarless Recipes/Sugar Rationing," and "Wartime Food Demonstration"
- Conservation: Fuel Oil 1942 Sep- Nov (Box 2)
  Includes "Health Measures for Low Home Temperatures," Home Insulation Conserves Fuel," and "How to Conserve Household Gas"
- Conservation: Gas Rationing 1942 Jun-Sep (Box 2)
- Conservation: Glass Gages Replacing Steel 1943 Jan (Box 2)
- Conservation: "I'll Carry Mine" Campaign 1942 Nov-Dec (Box 2)
- Conservation: Miscellaneous 1942-1943 (Box 2)
  Includes "Man-Hours," "Plastic Tableware for the Navy," "Substitutes--Glass Utensils and Timber Connections," and "Used Typewriter Campaign/Forty-Two Keys to Victory"
- Conservation: Point Rationing 1943 Feb, n.d. (Box 2)
- Conservation: Posters 1942-1943 (Box 2)
- Conservation 1942-1943 (Box 2)
  Includes "Reclaimed Rubber Heels," "Tire Recapping," and "Tire Retreading"
- Conservation: Scrap Iron and Steel 1942-1943 (Box 2)
- Conservation: Simplification of Clothing 1941-1943 (Box 2)
  Includes "Cotton Stockings"
- Conservation: Substitute Materials--Containers 1942 Sep (Box 2)
- Conservation: Truck Abuse/Neglect 1942 Apr, Jun (Box 2)
- Conservation/Salvage: Posters 1942 Aug (Box 2)
- Construction 1941-1942 (Box 2)
  Includes "New Tidal Basin Bridge, Washington, D.C."
- Conversion: Animal Traps to Armor-Piercing Bullet Cores 1942 Apr (Box 3)
- Conversion: Automobiles to Airplane Parts 1942 Feb, May (Box 3)
  Includes "Aircraft Landing Gear," "Airplane Engines," and "Airplane Parts"
- Conversion: Automobiles to Artillery Shells 1942 (Box 3)
  Includes "Artillery Shells," "40mm. A-A Guns," and "75 and 155 mm. Shells"
- Conversion: Automobiles to Jeeps, Trucks, and Tanks 1942 Feb, May (Box 3)
- Conversion: Automobiles to War Production 1942 Feb, Apr (Box 3)
- Conversion: Beverage Containers to Aviation Oxygen Cylinders 1942 Feb (Box 3)
- Conversion: Cash Registers to Gun Magazines 1942 Feb (Box 2)
- Conversion: Copper and Brass Processing 1942 Feb (Box 3)
- Conversion: Electric Shavers/Safety Razors to War Production 1942 Feb (Box 3)
- Conversion: Farm Implements to War Production 1942 Oct (Box 3)
  Includes "Cargo Winches" and "Gun Parts and 37 mm. Shells"
- Conversion: Flooring Products to War Production 1942 Feb (Box 3)
  Includes "Floor Waxers to War Production" and "Flooring to Gun Stocks"
- Conversion: Food Machinery to War Production 1942 Feb (Box 3)
- Conversion: Hosiery to Mosquito Netting 1942 Feb (Box 3)
- Conversion: Juke Boxes to Electrical Control Devices 1942 Feb (Box 3)
- Conversion: Merry-Go-Rounds to War Production 1942 (Box 3)
- Conversion: Metal Screens to Navigator Windows 1942 Mar (Box 3)
- Conversion: Oil Burners to Machine Gun Parts 1942 Feb (Box 3)
- Conversion: Pianos to Airplane Motors 1942 Jun (Box 3)
- Conversion: Safes and Locks to Guns and Gun Mounts 1942 Feb (Box 3)
- Conversion: Silverware to War Production 1942 Feb (Box 3)
- Conversion: Soft Drink Dispensers to War Production 1942 Feb (Box 3)
- Conversion: Toys to War Production 1942 Feb (Box 4)
  Includes "Toy Factory to War Production" and "Toy Furniture to Incendiary Bombs"
- Conversion: War Production Miscellaneous 1942 Feb-Jun (Box 4)
  Includes "Corn to Butylene Glycol," "Duck Decoys to Incendiary Bomb Noses," "Electric Refrigerators to Bombers and Searchlights," "Fuel Oil to Coal Heating System," "Garden Tools to Army Cot Parts," "Grain Alcohol to Butadiene," "Heaters to Bogie Wheels," "Paper Machinery to War Production," "Rubber Factory to War Production," "Plant Conversion," "Small Manufacturing to Aircraft Parts," and "Vulcanizing Tires to Self-Sealing Gas Tanks"
- Conversion: Watch Cases to War Production 1942 Feb (Box 4)
- Defense Housing: Erie, Pennsylvania 1941 Jul-Aug (Box 4)
- Defense Housing: Rental Areas 1941-1942 (Box 4)
  Includes "Government Hotel for Negro Women War Workers"
- Defense Housing: Tidewater, Virginia 1941 Jul (Box 4)
- Defense Housing: War Housing Trailers 1942 Mar-Jun (Box 4)
- Economy: Posters 1941-1943 (Box 4)
- Economy: Price Control 1942 May-Sep (Box 4)
- Economy: Shenandoah Valley, Virginia 1941-1943 (Box 4)
- Entertainment 1943-1944 (Box 4)
  Includes "Marian Anderson Mural Dedicated," "Theatre Productions--Operas" and "USO-Camp Shows Tour" Photographs of Fred Waring, Totimanna, Joan Blondell, Laurel and Hardy, Martha Raye, and Kay Francis and Mitzi Mayfair.
- Exhibitions 1944, n.d. (Box 4)
  Includes "History of the War, 'Paris, France" and "Power in the Pacific,'U.S. Navy Exhibit"
- Exhibitions 1941-1942 (Box 5)
  "The Four Freedoms" and "Arsenal of Democracy"
- Farm Security Administration 1935-1940 (Box 5)
  Includes "Small Town America" and "Tenant Farmers and Migrant Workers"
- Health and Welfare 1942-1944 (Box 5)
  Includes "Convalescence"
- Lend-Lease 1942-1943 (Box 5)
  Includes "Imported from the United States of America," "Lead-Lease India," "Lend-Lease Hearings," "Lead-Lease Loadings," "Lend-Lease Strikes at the Axis," and "Reciprocal Aid"
- Lend-Lease: Britain 1943 Mar (Box 5)
- Lend-Lease: Reciprocal Aid 194- (Box 5)
  Includes "Australia, New Zealand, Britain"
- Manpower: African-American Workers 1942 May (Box 5)
  Includes "Negro Aircraft Propeller Workers," "Negro Arsenal Workers," "Negro Bomber Plant Workers," "Negro Navy Yard/Shipyard Workers," "Negro Steel Workers," and "Miscellaneous Jobs--barber, lab tech, postman, lawyer, sculpture student--in New York"
- Manpower: Americans All 1942 Jul-Sep (Box 5)
- Manpower: Corpus Christi, Texas--Civil Service Employees 1942 Aug (Box 5)
- Manpower: Fort Story, Virginia 1942 (Box 6)
- Manpower: Langley Air Field, Virginia--YB-17 Bombardment Squadron 1942 May (Box 6)
- Manpower: Members of War Offices, Boards, etc 1941-1944 (Box 6)
- Manpower: Miscellaneous 1942 Mar-Aug (Box 6)
  Includes "Blue Island, Illinois--Senise family," "Elizabeth, New Jersey--Herbster family," "Frankfort, Pennsylvania--Smuda family," "Handicapped Workers," "Marine Combat Reporters," "Rochester, New York-- Babcock family," "Selective Service Inductions," "Veteran Boring Mill Worker," "Wisconsin--Saugstad family"
- Manpower: Miscellaneous A-F 194- (Box 6)
- Manpower: Miscellaneous G-O 194- (Box 6)
- Manpower: Miscellaneous P-Z 194- (Box 6)
- Manpower: Shipyard Workers 1942 May- Oct (Box 7)
  Includes "Baseball Players in War Production--Shipbuilding" Photographs of Vince DiMaggio, Vernie Stephens, and George Stovall
- Manpower: Training--Aviation 1942 Jul-Aug (Box 7)
  Includes "Brooklyn Aviation Center," Stewardess Training," and "Training High School Boys to Identify Planes"
- Manpower: Training--Fort Benning, Georgia 1942, 2 folders (Box 7)
- Manpower: Training--Fort Knox, Kentucky 1942, 2 folders (Box 7)
- Manpower: Training--Forts Belvoir, Monroe, and Myer, Virginia 1942 (Box 7)
- Manpower: Training--Maritime 1941-1943 (Box 7)
- Manpower: Training--New River, North Carolina 1942 May (Box 7)
- Manpower: Training--Nursing 1942-1943 (Box 7)
- Manpower: Training--Parris Island, South Carolina 1942 May, 2 folders (Box 7)
- Manpower: Training--W.P.A. Vocational School and Industry 1942 (Box 8)
- Manpower: Women Workers 1942, 2 folders (Box 8)
  Includes "Women Aircraft Workers," "Women Workers at Quartermaster Depot," "Women in Industry: Gas Mask Production," " Women in Industry: Tool Production," "Women in Military," "Women in War: Supercharger Plant Workers," "Women--Land Army (Farms)"
- Manpower: Women Workers 1943 (Box 8)
  Includes "Children of War-Working Mothers Alexandria, Virginia" and "Nursery Schools.. ."
- Manpower: Youth--Roanoke, Virginia 1942 Sep-Oct (Box 8)
- Maritime Activities 1942-1945 (Box 8)
  Includes "Convoy," "Lake Carrier," "Motor Torpedo Boats," and "U.S. Destroyer Murphy in Collision"
- Media 1943-1944 (Box 8)
  Includes "Iranian (Persian) Journalists" and "'Three Thirds of the Nation' radio program"
- Military Uniforms 1941-1942 (Box 8)
  Includes "Army: Helmuts and Caps," "Marines: Dress Parade," "Marines: Plastic Body Armor," and "Navy: Uniforms"
- National Defense Advisory Commission 1941, n.d. (Box 8)
- National Defense Advisory Commission: Commerical and Cultural Relations Office and Production Division 1942, n.d. (Box 8)
- National Defense Mediation Board 1942, n.d. (Box 9)
- National Parks of the United States 1942 (Box 9)
- Office Equipment 1942-1943 (Box 9)
  Includes "Horizontal Sorting Machine," "Office Equipment used by War Production Board," "Photographic Activities--Omega Enlarger," "Typewriters for Army, Navy, Marines," and "V-Mail"
- Office for Emergency Management 1942, n.d. (Box 9)
  Includes "Carl Sandburg" and "Information Division"
- Office of Civilian Defense 1941-1942 (Box 9)
  Includes "Eleanor Roosevelt"
- Office of Price Administration 1942, n.d. (Box 9)
  Includes "Consumer Division" and "Henderson Rally"
- Office of Production Managment 1942-1943, 2 folders (Box 9)
  Includes "Bureau of Industrial Conservation," "Civilian Supply", "Priorities Division," and "Purchase Division"
- Office of War Information 1942-1944, n.d. (Box 9)
  Includes "Elmer Davis, Director," "News Bureau," and "Oversees Branches"
- Portrait of America: An American Country Auction 1943 (Box 10)
- Portrait of America: City Children have Vacation o U.S. Farms 1943 (Box 10)
- Portrait of America: Floating Hospital serves U.S. Children 1943 (Box 10)
- Portrait of America: Health in a U.S. City: A Serum and Vaccine Farm 1943 (Box 10)
- Portrait of America: How U.S. Movies are Made 1943 (Box 10)
- Portrait of America: Nantucket, Historic American Whaling Port 1943 (Box 10)
- Portrait of America: Small Towns 1943 (Box 10)
- Portrait of America: U.S. Amusement Parks 1943 (Box 10)
- Portrait of America: Vassar--A Famous American College for Women 1943 (Box 10)
- Production: Aviation--Aircraft Engines 1942 Feb-Jul (Box 10)
- Production: Aviation--Aircraft Fuel Tanks and Propellors 1942 Feb-Jun (Box 10)
- Production: Aviation--Aircraft Parts 1941 Dec (Box 10)
  Includes "Airplane Flotation Bags," "Aircraft Life Boats," and "Subcontracting"
- Production: Aviation--Airplant Manufacture--Douglas Aircraft Company, Long Beach California 1942 Oct (Box 10)
- Production: Aviation--Airplant Manufacture--North American Aviation, Inglewood, California 1942 Oct, 2 folders (Box 11)
- Production: Aviation--Airplant Manufacture--Theatres of Operation 1942-1943 (Box 11)
- Production: Aviation--Airplane Manufacture--western airplane factories and others 1942 Apr-Aug (Box 11)
  Includes "Deland Pool, Florida"
- Production: Aviation--Bombers 1942 Jun-Oct (Box 11)
  Includes "A-20 Attack Bombers," "B-24 Bombers and C-87 Transports," "Ventura Bombers," and "Willow Run Bomber Plant"
- Production: Aviation--Bombers--B-17 Bombers--"Flying Fortress" 1942 Oct-Dec (Box 11)
  Includes "Douglas Aircraft Company, in Long Beach, California" and "in Seattle, Washington"
- Production: Aviation--Bombers--B-24 Bombers and C-87 Transports 1942 Oct (Box 11)
- Production: Aviation--Bombers--B-24E "Liberator" 1943 Feb (Box 11)
- Production: Aviation--Bombers--B-25 Bombers 1942 Jun-Jul (Box 11)
- Production: Aviation--Bombers--B-25 Bomber--"Billy Mitchell' 1942 Jun-Jul (Box 11)
- Production: Aviation--Bombers--Mitchell Field 1942 Apr (Box 11)
- Production: Aviation--Fighter Planes--P-51"Mustang" 1942 Oct (Box 12)
- Production: Aviation--Parachutes 1942 Jul-Aug (Box 12)
- Production: Aviation--Pursuit Planes--Lockheed P-38 1942 Nov (Box 12)
- Production: Aviation--Transport Planes--C-47 1942 (Box 12)
- Production: Chemicals 1942-1943 (Box 12)
  Includes "(synthetic) Ammonia," "Magnesium," "Mercury," and "Phosphorous (elemental)"
- Production: Deland Industrial Pool 1942 Mar-Apr (Box 12)
  Includes "Bits and Parts," "Carr's Machine Shop," "Improvised Foundry, Daytona Beach," "LaRoe Shop," "Moving Circus," "Sewing Plane Wing Fabric," and "Skilled Craftsmen"
- Production: Engines 1941-1942 (Box 12)
- Production: Ford River Rouge Plant, Dearborn, Michigan 1941 (Box 12)
- Production: Fuel--Anthracite 1942 (Box 12)
- Production: Glass--"Fiberglas" and Ceramics 1942 Feb (Box 12)
  Includes "Shenango Pottery Works, China"
- Production: Lubricants--Oil, et al 1941 Sep (Box 12)
- Production: Lumber 1941-1942 (Box 12)
- Production: Maritime--Shipbuilding--Boats and General 1941-1942 (Box 12)
  Includes "Assault Boats," "B-T-13A 'Valiant' Basic Trainers," Motor Torpedo Boats (wooden)," "Rickenbacker Rescue Boats," and "Steel Ramp Boats"
- Production: Maritime--Shipbuilding--Brooklyn Navy Yard 1941 (Box 13)
- Production: Maritime--Shipbuilding--Engines and Parts 1941-1943 (Box 13)
  Includes "Engine for Navy Mosquito Fleet," "Hatch Assembly," "Ship Propellers," and "Bits and Pieces Display"
- Production: Maritime--Shipbuilding--"Liberty" Ships 1941-1942 (Box 13)
  Includes "Booker T. Washington"
- Production: Maritime--Shipbuilding--Mine Sweepers 1942 Apr (Box 13)
- Production: Maritime--Shipbuilding--Newport News and Norfolk, Virginia 1941 Oct (Box 13)
- Production: Maritime--Submarine Chasers and Submarines 1942 Mar-Aug (Box 13)
- Production: Medical--Blood Transfusion Bottle 1942 Oct (Box 13)
- Production: Metals--Aluminum 1941-1942 (Box 13)
- Production: Metals--Milling Machines and Machine Castings 1941-1942 (Box 13)
- Production: Metals--Miscellaneous 1942-1943 (Box 13)
  Includes "Alloy," "Cooper," "Tin Smelting," "Zinc," and "Locomotives"
- Production: Metals--Pipe Fittings 1942 Jan (Box 14)
- Production: Metals--Steel 1941 (Box 14)
- Production: Miscellaneous 1941-1942 (Box 14)
  Includes "Army Tents," "Barrage Balloons," "Clothing: Army Uniform Trousers and Underware," "Factories--Heinz, New Jersey," "Industrial Alcohol for making explosives," and "Wagon Wheels"
- Production: Passaic Home Worshop Pool 1942 Mar (Box 14)
- Production: Posters 1942 (Box 14)
- Production: Power 1942-1943 (Box 14)
  Includes "Dante Electric Company, Bantam, Connecticut," "Electric Power," and "Norris Powerhouse and accompanying photographs"
- Production: Power--Marine Boilers 1942 Jan-Feb (Box 14)
- Production: Power--Steam Power Plant Equipment 1942 Jun (Box 14)
- Production: Power--Transformer Manufacture 1942 Feb (Box 14)
- Production: Rubber--Synthetic Rubber 1942 Feb (Box 14)
- Production: Rubber--Tire Manufacture 1941-1942 (Box 14)
- Production: Tanks 1941-1943 (Box 14)
  Includes "M-1, M-7, M-10 Tanks," "M-4 Tanks," "Tank Armor," and "Trackless Tanks"
- Production: Tanks--M-3 Tanks 1942 (Box 14)
- Production: Vehicles--Army Trucks 1941-1942 (Box 15)
- Production: Vehicles--Halftrac Scout Cars 1941 Dec (Box 15)
- Production: Vehicles--Miscellaneous 1941 May, Dec (Box 15)
  Includes "Blitz Buggies," "Halftrac Tracks for Army Vehicles," "Jeeps," and "Semi-Trailers"
- Production: Warren McArthur Plants, Bantam, Connecticut 1942 (Box 15)
- Production: Weaponry--Firearms 1942 Jul (Box 15)
  Includes ".45 Caliber Automatic Pistols and .38 Caliber Revolvers," "Garand Rifle," and "Medium and Major Caliber Guns"
- Production: Weaponry--Government Arsenals 1942 (Box 15)
- Production: Weaponry--Machine Guns 1942 Feb-Jul (Box 15)
  Includes "20 mm. Machine Guns for Planes"
- Production: Weaponry--Mounts and Carriages 1941-1943 (Box 15)
  Includes "Aiming Apparatus," "Anti-Aircraft Carriages/Catridges," "Bofor 40 mm. Mounts and Carriages," "M-7 Mobile Howitzer Carriage," and "Naval Gun Mounts"
- Production: Weaponry--Shells and Catridge Cases 1941-1943 (Box 15)
  Includes "3" AA Cartridge Cases," "Armor Piercing Shells," "20mm. Shell Boosters," "75 mm. Shells and Catridge Cases," and "55 mm. Shells"
- Production: Torpedoes 194- (Box 16)
- Propaganda 1942 Apr (Box 16)
  Includes "Hitler's Helpmates," "Inflation--Hitler's Ally," "The Nature of the Enemy," and "You Can't do Business with Hitler"
- Propaganda: Posters 1942 (Box 16)
- Religion 1943-1945 (Box 16)
- Relocation: Japanese Ancestry 1942 (Box 16)
  Includes "Territory of Hawaii--Americans of Japanese ancestry enlist"
- Resettlement Administration 1935-1940, 3 folders (Box 16)
  Includes "Greenbelt, Maryland" and "Mid-West Flood of 1937"
- Safety 1942-1943 (Box 16)
- Salvage: Automobiles 1942 May-Sep (Box 16)
- Salvage: Greases 1942 Jun (Box 17)
- Salvage: Hattiesburg, Mississippi 1942 Apr (Box 17)
- Salvage: Metals 1941-1943 (Box 17)
  Includes "Aluminum," "Marine Iron and Steel Scrap," and "Tin"
- Salvage: Miscellaneous 1942 (Box 17)
  Includes "Rags and Waste Paper," "Rural/Farm Scrap," "Discarded Silk Stocking," and "Wool Reclamation"
- Salvage: Rubber 1941-1942 (Box 17)
- Tennessee Valley Authority 1942 (Box 17)
  Includes "Power for the Defense"
- Tennessee Valley Authority: Power and Conservation--Dam Construction 1942 Jun (Box 17)
  Includes "Chicamauga Dam," "Douglas Dam," and "Fort Loudon Dam"
- Tennessee Valley Authority: Power and Conservation--Hydroelectric Plan Construction 1942 Jun (Box 17)
  Includes "Watts Bar Dam" and "Wilson Dam"
- Theatres of Operation: African and Mediterranean Theatres 1943 (Box 17)
  Includes "South Africa's Army Girls," "American 'Steam Chickens' (P-40 Fighter Plane) arrive in Africa," "Egypt," Ethopia," "Gold Coast Battery and other British/African Squadrons," "Liberia," "Libya, esp. Tripoli," "Middle East," "Tunisia," and "Turkey"
- Theatres of Operation: European Theatre--England and elsewhere, inc. Germany; and, Atlantic Theatre--North and South America 1943-1945 (Box 18)
- Theatres of Operation: European Theatre--France and Italy 1944 (Box 18)
- Theatres of Operation: Far East Theatre--Asia 1942-1945 (Box 18)
  Includes "Burma," "Formosa (Taiwan)," "India," "India--American Flying Squadron," "Indonesia," "Japan," and "Philippines"
- Theatres of Operation: Far East Theatre: Asia--Hong Kong 1942, legal size box (Box 20)
- Theatres of Operation: Far East Theatre--Persian Corridor--Supplies for Russia 1943 (Box 18)
- Theatre of Operation: Pacific Theatre 1943 (Box 18)
  Includes "Naval Aviation Observes 31st Anniversary" and "South Pacific--Marine Corps 'Black Sheep' Squadron"
- Theatres of Operation: Pacific Theatre--Oceania 1942-1945 (Box 18)
  Includes "Aleutian Islands," "Gilbert Islands," "Guam," "Hawaii--Airfield Security Detachment," "Hawaii--Pearl Harbor," "Iwo Jima," "Marcus Island," "Mariana Islands," "Midway Island," "New Britain," and "New Caledonia"
- Theatres of Operation: Pacific Theatre--Oceania--Australia 1943-1944 (Box 18)
- Transportation 1942-1943 (Box 18)
  Includes "Lend-Lease Shipments"
- Transportation: Car-Pooling 1942 May-Jun (Box 19)
- United States Army Miscellaneous 1941 (Box 19)
  Includes "U.S. Army Pays Medical Students to be Educated"
- United States Coast Guard Miscellaneous 1943-1945 (Box 19)
  Includes "Auxillary"
- United States Navy Miscellaneous 1943-1945 (Box 19)
- Victory Campaigns 1943 (Box 19)
  Includes "Shopping for Victory with War Bonds," "Victory Book Campaign," "Victory Food--From American Waters," "Victory Garden--For Family and Country," and "Victory Stores"
- Victory Campaigns: "A Poster Comes to Life" 1942 Aug (Box 19)
- Victory Corps: High Schools 1942 (Box 19)
  Includes "Los Angeles, California: Polytechnic High School, Roosevelt High School,and Washington High School," "Silver Spring, Maryland: Montgomery Blair High School and Washington, D. C.: McKinley Technical High School," and "New York, New York: Benjamin Franklin High School and Queens, New York: Flushing High School"
- War Manpower Commission 1942, n.d. (Box 19)
- War Production Board 1941-1942, n.d. (Box 19)
- War Production Drive 1941-1943 (Box 19)
- War Production Drive: Citations of Individual Production Merit 1942, n.d. (Box 19)
  Includes President Roosevelt with Citation Winners